Yang Song

2009 Greene Street Apartment 502 Columbia, SC 29205 www.cse.sc.edu/~song24 song24@email.sc.edu 803-381-1667

Summary

Developed advanced planning algorithms for mobile robots. Familiar with motion planning, robot dynamics and control. Proficient in robotics programming on Linux platforms using C++, Java, and Python, with third-party libraries (ROS). Experienced with mobile robot platforms: Pioneer, Turtlebot, etc.

EDUCATION

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC

Ph.D. Candidate, Computer Science

Dec. 2015

University of New Mexico, Albuquerque, NM

M.S., Electrical Engineering

Dec. 2009

China University of Geosciences, Wuhan, Hubei

B.S., Electrical Engineering

June 2007

Research Experience

South Carolina Autonomous Robotics Research (SCARR) Lab, USC

Decentralized Formation Algorithm for Multi-Robot Systems Aug. 2014 – Present

- Proposed a provably-correct decentralized multi-robot formation algorithm
- Developed ROS-based software simulations with C++, Python and Bash
- Designed and built a GUI with the GTK+ and the Boost libraries

SCARR Lab, USC

Distributed Formation Algorithm for Multi-Robot Systems Aug. 2013 – May 2014

- Innovated a distributed task-assignment-based formation algorithm for multi-robot systems
- Implemented the algorithm and simulated experiments with C++
- Supported by the National Science Foundation (NSF) grant

SCARR Lab, USC

Planning Algorithm under Uncertainty

Aug. 2010 – May 2011

- Promoted a geometric algorithm for robot planning under uncertainty
- Accomplished the algorithm and simulations using C++
- Achieved the same level of performance as using the approach that computed the high-fidelity information states, but with a small fraction of computational cost
- Supported by the NSF grant

Multi-Agent, Robotics, Hybrid, and Embedded Systems (MARHES) Lab, UNM

Multi-Robot Control Algorithm

Aug. 2009

- Implemented a cyclic pursuit algorithm for nonholonomic vehicles with Matlab/C++
- Simulated algorithms with Player/Gazebo
- Conducted experiments with Pioneer robots

Honors & Awards

Member of Upsilon Pi Epsilon NSF Student Travel Grant Award

May 2014

Code-A-Thon Winner (2 out of 12 teams)

Feb. 2014

C/C++, Python, Ruby, Java, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, LATEX Language & Tools ROS, Git, CMake, MATLAB, OpenCV, Bootstrap, Boost

TEACHING

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC

EXPERIENCE

General Application Programming June 2012 – May 2014

- Taught web front-end interface design using HTML/CSS/JavaScript Jan. 2012 – May 2012

Introduction to Computer Architecture

- Taught computer architecture and MIPS programming Algorithmic Design I Aug. 2010 – May 2011

- Instructed problem-solving patterns, algorithmic design, and Java programming

Publications Y. Song and J. M. O'Kane, "Decentralized formation of arbitrary multi-robot lattices", ICRA 2014.

> Y. Song and J. M. O'Kane, "Comparison of constrained geometric approximation strategies for planar information states", ICRA 2012.

> D. Miklic, S. Bogdan, R. Fierro, Y. Song, "A grid-based approach to formation reconfiguration for a class of robots with non-holonomic constraints", European Journal of Control, 2012.